We stand today at the threshold of a great event.
我们站在联合国历史
Both in the life of the United Nations and in the life of mankind.
也是人类历史上的伟大起点
This universal declaration of human rights may well become
这份人权宣言很可能会成为
the international Magna Carta of all men everywhere.
世界上所有人的国际大宪章
You only meet your once-in-a-lifetime friend once in a lifetime,
一辈子只有一次机会 可以遇到一生挚友
and I had to travel a long way to realize that.
我走了很长一段路 才意会到这点
That October, I'd just turned 15 years old.
那年十月，我刚满15岁
My mother was dead, and I thought it was my fault.
我的母亲刚过世 我为此责怪自己
Home was the last place I wanted to be.
我完全不想待在家中
I wanted it to swallow me up.
我想就此放弃
- But she wouldn't let it. - Thank goodness you're home.
但她不让我这么做
Can I run through my speech with you one more time?
我能再跟你练习一次我的演讲吗？
I'm tired of hearing that stupid speech.
我受够了那愚蠢的演讲
I just want to make sure I've memorized it and left nothing out when I introduce her.
我只是想确认我都有背下来 介绍她的时候不要漏掉内容
And I'm nervous.
而且我很紧张
I'm sure Mrs. Roosevelt won't mind if you leave something out.
我确信罗斯福夫人不会介意 你漏掉一两件事
You should come with me to hear Mrs. Roosevelt.
你应该跟我一起去 听罗斯福女士的演讲
You're the future of this country. You and Max the Wax, God forbid.
你是国家未来的主人翁 天啊，你跟伟大的瓦克斯都是
I mean, things are hard for women today.
当今世道女性很难生存
When are you gonna learn that women need to stick together?
你什么时候才会了解 我们女性要团结合作
I stick together. Me and Max the Wax are going to the movies later to see Gidget.
我有合作啊，我和伟大的瓦克斯 晚点要去看《玉女春潮》
Would you at least pick Henry up from school so that I'm not late?
那你至少能帮我去接亨利 让我不用迟到吗？
No! Let the little wiener walk. I had to.
叫那个臭小子跟我一样用走的
Thanks a lot. Dinner is in the oven, make a vegetable and I don't mean corn.
真谢谢你，晚餐就在烤箱里 记得吃蔬菜，玉米不算
One of the most famous stars in Hollywood history is dead at 36.
好莱坞最闪亮的一颗新星英年早逝 享年36岁
Marilyn Monroe was found dead in bed
玛丽莲梦露陈尸在床上
under circumstances that were in tragic contrast
当时介于她如日中天的事业
to her glamorous career as a comic talent.
被公认为是一场大悲剧
On the surface, she seemed to have such a sensible mind...
从外表上看起来 她是一个很敏感的人…
She was fate because of me.
她因为我而迟到
She was hit by a car.
她出了车祸
My mother loved Eleanor Roosevelt.
我的母亲很爱爱莲娜罗斯福
She said she was the greatest First Lady our country ever had.
她说她是这国家 最伟大的第一夫人
Women gotta stick together, don't you know?
你不知道吗？ 女性必须团结合作
- Why can't we have corn? - No more corn.
为什么我们不能吃玉米？ 没有玉米了
Is Dad gonna eat?
爸爸要一起吃吗？
I don't know. He's busy.
我不知道，他很忙
He's always busy. I wish he'd be a pumpkin man again.
他总是在忙 希望他能再扮一次南瓜人
We're not pumpkin people no more because Mom's gone,
我们不能再扮南瓜人了 因为妈妈过世了
and he don't give a flip about pumpkins no more.
他再也不管南瓜的事了
Heck, I don't think he'd even notice if one of us went missing.
算了，就算我们之间有人不见 他八成也不会注意到
This don't taste like sloppy joe. I wish Mom could make it.
这尝起来一点也不像肉酱 我想要吃妈妈做的
It's Mom's same recipe, so quit complaining.
这是妈妈留下来的食谱 不要再抱怨了
- And we're still a family. - I'm itchy.
我们还是家人 我身体痒
Me, too.
我也是
It's because you have the chicken pox.
那是因为你们都得了水痘
I'm next, ain't I?
我会不会接着遭殃？
Warren!
沃伦！
Marilyn, rest in peace.
玛莉莲，愿你安息
And RIP Jesus.
耶稣也是
Elvis?
猫王？
You chewed up my letter!
你把我的信给咬烂了
- I'm gonna have a serious talk with you... - "Dear Eleanor...
“亲爱的爱莲娜… 等我到家后
- ...when I get home. - "...my name is Maxine Wax,
要好好教训你 “…我叫麦斯
"and I'm 15 years old.
“今年15岁
"You may have already heard of me as my family is very famous."
“你可能听过我的事 我的家人非常有名”
Keep reading.
继续读
"I'm writing to you because my best friend Ellie has gone berserk
“我写信给你，是因为我的朋友 艾莉最近一直在发脾气
"and practically lost her mind.
“她快变成疯子了
"Her mom died this last summer, and I know it would mean a lot to her
“她的母亲去年夏天去世 我确信如果她能跟你见一面
"if she could meet you and get some words of encouragement
“并请你当面鼓励她 她一定会很高兴
- "from a real trooper." - Okay, skip to the end.
“得到长官的鼓励” 跳到最后
Right there, Billy.
比利，就在那
"Sincerely, sincerely, Maxine Wax.
“麦斯瓦克斯致上
"P.S. You're probably a very busy person.
“附注，你八成是位大忙人
"You can just send her an autographed picture of yourself
“你可以寄给她你的亲笔签名照
"because that would be neat, too.
“那样也不错
"Thanks, Mrs. Roosevelt."
“谢谢，罗斯福夫人”
I liked maps.
我喜欢地图
I could look at the State Farm Road Atlas for hours.
我能盯着州际农村道路好几个小时
Opening it gave you a sense of adventure, and that everything was possible.
光是打开地图就像在经历一场冒险 好像所有事情都有可能
Ellie!
艾莉！
And that you could plot a new life for yourself.
好像你可以计划一场新的人生
And the red-lined highways would take you there.
代表高速公路的红线 可以戴你到任何地方
Ellie, are you up there?
艾莉，你在楼上吗？
Max the Wax and I are going to Dairy Deluxe! Wanna come?
伟大的瓦克斯跟我要去豪华餐馆吃饭！ 要跟吗？
Yeah, hold on.
等一下
Hi, Annabell.
嗨，安娜贝儿
Say...
跟…
Say, "Hey, Max."
跟麦斯打招呼
Okay.
好吧
Come here.
站好
Don't fall. Don't fall.
不要跌倒
Hey, look out for her.
好好照顾她
- What, come on! - You promised!
为什么？ 你答应过我的！
Hey, did you guys know that Manteca is the pumpkin capital of the world?
你们知道曼特卡是世界上的南瓜首府吗？
I'm serious. Without Manteca there wouldn't even be a Halloween.
我是认真的，没有曼特卡 就没有万圣节
- Hey, Billy. - Don't. Don't start with that again.
嘿，比利 不要再讲了
- Billy! - You guys know that
比利！ 你们知道
- I do not like that, Max! - Billy!
我不喜欢这样，麦斯！ 比利！
There's your dad, sitting in his truck staring at nothing again.
你爸又坐在车里发呆
Come on, let's go.
我们走吧
Saturdays, we confessed. Max loved to confess.
每个星期六，我们都会去告解 麦斯最爱告解了
One time she was in there for two whole hours.
有一次她在里面待了整整两个小时
But I knew my sin was so bad, no amount of Hail Marys could save me.
但我知道我犯的罪太重了 就连圣母玛利亚也救不了我
You're up.
换你了
I got nine Our Fathers, 10 Hail Marys and six Acts of Contrition.
我让牧师讲了九次我们的天父 十次圣母玛利亚，还有六次悔悟行为
And they want to see me again next week.
他们希望我下礼拜再来一次
After confession, we'd go to the movies with our cleansed souls.
在告解完后 我们会带着洗涤过的灵魂去电影院
We were good for the first two minutes,
前两分钟都相安无事
and then impure thoughts about Warren Beatty would creep in.
然后就会开始意淫华伦比提
We're going to hell.
我们会下地狱
I understand, that's probably a good idea. Hi.
我懂的，那八成是个好主意，嗨
I'll give you $250. That's more than fair.
我可以付你250块 这价钱很公道
$250?
250块？
I'm sure it is fair, but Carolina's piano is not for sale.
当然很公道 但我不卖卡罗琳的钢琴
- $300.
300块
- Why is your mouth blue, son? - Don't know, sir.
小子，为什么你的嘴巴是蓝的？ 先生，我不知道
- Jack, go wash your face, okay? - I did, and it don't come off.
杰克，去洗脸，好吗？ 我洗了，但洗不掉
The thing is, we're gonna keep the piano, all right?
我们就是要把钢琴留着，好吗？
Come here, come on.
过来这边
Oh, my Lord, me, too. Come here.
我的天啊，让我抱抱
You're hot.
你好烫
It's all right.
没事的
Come on.
乖
Let's go find him, come on.
我们快去找他
Nothing.
没事
Couple of little ladies headed your way.
有几位年轻妹妹来找你唷
Shit.
该死的
Third one's got it. Fourth one's gonna get it.
第三个人了 第四个马上就会得了
- Get what? - Chicken pox.
得什么？ 水痘
I'm not gonna get it because I already had it.
我不会得，因为我得过了
But now she's running a fever and she won't stop crying,
但她在发烧，而且哭个不停
and somebody's got to take her temperature and I'm not gonna do it.
得有人帮她量体温 我才不干
Why not?
为什么？
Because it goes up her butt, that's why.
因为要碰到她屁股
She needs to go to a doctor, but I'm not grown-up
她得去看医生，我又不是大人
and I'm not her parent so you gotta do it,
也不是她父母 所以得由你来做
or you can do this.
或者你可以量体温
- Okay. - You are on your own, buddy.
好吧 兄弟，好自为之
I'll be in the car.
我在车里等
I'm gonna concede this game.
看来这场我得先投降
Dr. Henning to pediatrics. Dr. Henning to pediatrics, please.
请亨宁医生到小儿科
Hi. Thank you.
嗨，谢谢你
Give her baby aspirin until her fever reduces.
我给她婴儿用的阿斯匹灵到她烧退了
Okay.
好的
She don't look too bad.
她没什么大碍
- I'm trying, Ellie. - Not hard enough, Dad.
艾莉，我尽我所能了 爸，还不够好
- She still sleeping? - Yeah.
她还在睡吗？ 对
All the kids are home sick today,
其他人也请病假
so you're gonna have to stay here and take care of them.
你必须待在家里照顾他们
I have a big history test I can't miss.
我不能错过历史考试
Okay, well, I'll...
好吧，那我就…
I'll call Grandma and...
打给外婆和…
There's a party at Tom's tonight.
汤姆他家今天晚上要办派对
- You want to come over? - No, no, daddy-o.
要来吗？ 没办法
I'm going to Motorcycle Rita's to get drunk and have sex and do drugs.
我要去重机王瑞塔家喝个大醉 然后疯狂做爱跟嗑药
No doll's called Motorcycle Rita.
才没有娃娃会叫重机王瑞塔
Yes, there is. And that's where Marijuana Millie's going tonight.
当然有，我的大麻米莉今晚就要去那
No doll's named Marijuana.
才没有娃娃会叫大麻
Okay, maybe not your dolls,
好吧，说不定你的娃娃不会
but my dolls do a lot of interesting things yours would never do.
但比起你的娃娃 我的娃娃会做很多有趣的事情
Well, my dolls like to go camping all the time at Lake Don Pedro.
我的娃娃最喜欢 去唐佩德罗湖边露营
And eat tacos and swim.
吃墨西哥脆饼和游泳
Who cares about tacos and Lake Don Pedro?
谁在乎脆饼跟唐佩德罗湖
What's been up with you lately?
你最近是怎么了？
I thought we were playing dolls and having fun and stuff like that,
我以为我们只是在玩娃娃跟找乐子
and all of a sudden your doll is out of control.
你的娃娃突然就失控了
- Millie used to own a bakery. - She sold it.
米莉曾经有过一间面包坊 她卖掉了
Can't be naked and own a bakery.
她不能当个裸女又开面包坊
I'm going home.
我要回家了
Wait.
等一下
I thought we were gonna make s'mores,
我以为我们要一起做棉花糖夹心饼
and camp out in the backyard with the Little Elvis and play records all night long.
然后跟小猫王在后院露营 听整晚的歌
It's not gonna be any fun if it's just me and him.
只有我跟他一点也不好玩
Aren't we a little old to be playing with dolls?
你不觉得我们已经过了 玩娃娃的年纪了吗？
Yeah, that'll be the day.
不可能的
I'll see you later.
晚点见
Come on. Ellie's all right.
艾莉不会有事
You have no idea how bad it is, Billy.
你不知道她的状况有多糟
She's no fun anymore. She doesn't even want to play dolls.
她不再是以前的开心果 她甚至不想玩娃娃
You guys still play dolls?
你们还在玩娃娃？
Stop giving me the business.
不要再批评我
How would an autographed picture of Mrs. Roosevelt make Ellie be fun again?
爱莲娜女士的签名照 要如何让艾莉变回开心果？
It just would.
就是会
Billy, I'm 15 years old, okay?
比利，我已经15岁了，好吗？
Fifteen is the age when girls start to lose it and Ellie's almost 16.
女生满15岁后就会破处 艾莉已经快满16岁了
- So what do you think that means? - I really...
你认为那代表什么？ 我…
- I really have no idea. - Of course, you're a boy.
我也不知道 当然，你是男生
Are you going to the Rock Around the Clock hop?
你要去摇滚时刻演唱会吗？
If no other fellow has asked you to go, we could go together.
要是没有人邀你的话 我们可以一起去
I mean, I'm sure... I'm sure that you have a lot of guys you like, so.
我确…确信 你一定有很多男生可以挑
Listen, Billy, 'cause I'm only gonna say this once.
比利，听着 因为我只会说一次
I know you think us girls think about you guys all the time, but we don't.
我知道你们认为女生 满脑子都在想男生的事，并没有
Okay?
好吗？
So I'll see you soon.
晚点见
And next time, can I have my cone swirled instead of just plain vanilla?
下次不要给我香草口味 可以给我综合口味的吗？
And can you dip it, too, please?
还有帮我沾点酱，拜托？
- Yeah, sure. - Au revoir.
当然 再见
"Dear Max,
“亲爱的麦斯
"thank you so much for your letter.
“很高兴收到你的信
"At the moment, I'm out of pictures of myself.
“目前我的照片刚好都用完了
"But I was thinking
“但我刚刚想到
"maybe someday you and your friend Ellie
“说不定你跟你的朋友，艾莉
"can come to visit me at my home in New York.
“可以来我位于纽约的家拜访我
"Sincerely, Eleanor Roosevelt."
“爱莲娜罗斯福致上”
Now you look like you came from New York.
看起来就像纽约寄来的信
- Don't forget to check the mail, by the way. - All right.
不要忘记去看有没有信 好的
Guess what? Okay, I wrote a letter to Eleanor Roosevelt
猜怎么着？ 我写信给爱莲娜罗斯福
to get an autographed picture for you and she wrote me back,
帮你要一张她的签名照 而且她回信了
and she wants to meet us, so pack your bags because we're going to New York!
她想见我们，打包好行李 因为我们要去纽约！
We're going to New York!
我们要去纽约！
Gee whiz!
扫兴！
...rainfall have left many homes in the metro area knee deep in floodwater.
…大雨让大都会区很多住家都面临淹水
Power was out for three hours in eastern metro
因为地下管线问题 东部城区已经停电
because of downed hydro-fines and police report at feast 200 accidents.
长达三小时 警方也接获多达200起事故
No injuries were reported.
目前无人受伤
The search for escaped prisoner Frank Morris and the Anglin brothers has been called off.
追捕逃犯法兰克莫利斯 和安格林兄弟的行动已经停止
The three escaped from Alcatraz five months ago,
这三人五个月前逃离阿卡翠斯监狱
but no bodies have been recovered.
目前没有发现任何尸体
I don't know why I said those things to my mother.
我不知道自己为什么 要对母亲说那种话
I regretted them the second they fell out of my mouth.
说出口当下我就后悔
My mother never gave her speech.
我妈来不及去演讲
She never got to meet Eleanor Roosevelt.
她没有见到爱莲娜罗斯福
But I could.
但我可以
Heads,
正面
I go.
我就去
Tails,
反面
I don't.
我就不去
We're gonna get to see the whole country, Ellie.
艾莉，我们可以见识整个国家
- Gosh, I love America. - You've never even been out of Manteca,
天啊，我超爱美国 你连曼特卡都没离开过
and New York's a metropolis. And you can't drive.
纽约是个大都会 你也不会开车
Yeah, I can. My mom was a feminist. She taught me early.
我会，我妈很重视女权 所以我很小她就教过我
Yeah, her mom's a feminist, and I'm gonna be one, too.
对，她妈很重视女权 我也要变成那样
You don't even know what that means.
你连那是什么意思都不知道
It means you're gonna stay home and take care of the Little Elvis, Billy!
比利，意思就是你要待在家照顾小猫王
Do you think she's gonna make us recite the pledge of allegiance?
你认为她会叫我们背效忠誓词吗？
Maybe.
可能吧
She wrote to you. Why can't you be satisfied with that?
她回信了 你们为什么还不满足？
We should go visit my Aunt Daisy in Las Vegas.
我们要去拉斯维加斯 拜访我的黛西婶婶
And I also want to stop by the actor studio to give that Lee Strasberg a holler.
我也要去片厂跟李史特拉斯堡打招呼
- Who's Lee Strasberg? - Wait, who's Aunt Daisy?
那是谁？ 等等，谁是黛西婶婶？
I got a picture of her right here.
我有一张她的照片
- What happened to her head? - Little Elvis ate her face off.
她的头怎么了？ 小猫王把她的脸咬掉了
She's really cool. She's a showgirl and she has her own theater on the strip.
她很酷，她是跳舞女郎 在大道上还有自己的剧院
This is gonna be so boss.
这趟旅行一定酷毙了
So we're gonna skip school on Friday,
我们把星期五的课翘掉
and I'll tell my dad I'm staying with you over the weekend,
我跟我爸说我周末要去你家住
and you tell your mom you're staying with me over the weekend,
你告诉你妈 你周末要来我家住
and then when they find out, we'll already be long gone.
当他们发现时 我们已经远走高飞
You two don't have no money.
你们一毛钱都没有
Shut your mouth, Billy. I know where we can get some.
比利，你闭嘴 我知道要去哪弄钱
Yeah. Stop giving us the business, Billy. We know where we can get some money.
对呀，比利，不要再扫兴 我们知道要去哪弄钱
Why are you touching Mom's piano?
你干嘛碰妈妈的钢琴？
I can touch it if I want.
我想碰就碰
Dad don't want no one touching Mama's piano.
爸不希望任何人摸妈妈的钢琴
If I told you a good secret, would you help me out?
要是我跟你们讲个秘密 你们会帮我吗？
But you have to promise not to tell a soul, not even Dad.
但你们得先发誓不跟任何人讲 包括老爸
Dad don't want me keeping secrets from him!
老爸不希望我对他隐瞒任何事！
I'm doing something for Mom.
我是为了妈做的
But to do it,
但要做这件事
I have to sell her piano.
我得把她的钢琴卖掉
And if she were here right now, she'd be okay with it
要是她在这，她也会同意的
because people are more important than stuff, right?
因为人比物品重要，对吧？
I'll give you 5 bucks.
我会分五块给你们
My mom and Marilyn Monroe died on the same day.
我妈跟玛丽莲梦露在同一天过世
I imagined Marilyn picking my mom up like some kind of girls' night out.
我想玛丽莲梦露 一定有找我妈去过闺蜜之夜
Just the two of them.
就她们两个
The 1948 Chrysler Windsor with a drop top in Robin's egg blue?
淡青色的1948年的克莱斯勒温莎敞篷车？
- The very one. - Smile!
没错 笑一个！
We're going to New York!
我们要去纽约了！
They'd hop into Marilyn's pink Thunderbird and hit the road.
她们一定会开玛莉莲的粉红色雷鸟上路
Didn't seem so lonely.
看起来一点也不孤独
Seemed nice.
一定很棒
V-A-C-A-T-I-O-N, in the summer sun!
假期，还有夏日！
Put away the books, we're out of school
把书收起来，学校放假了
The weather's warm but we play it cool
暖暖的天气配上酷酷的我们
We're on vacation in the summer sun!
在夏天的太阳之下 我们放假了！
How many miles to New York?
离纽约还有多远？
3,000
4800公里
- You kidding me? - No.
你在开玩笑吗？ 没有
And here is our money.
这是我们的钱
That's all we've got so put it in a safe spot, okay?
只有这些了 要好好保管，好吗？
Holy moly, that's a lot of moolah.
我的天啊，有够多银子的
I don't think I've ever seen this much money in my whole life.
我这辈子没看过这么多钱
- All safe. - Great.
安全无虞 很好
Okay, I was gonna wait,
我本来想再等一下
but since we're about to have the time of our lives...
但既然我们将要踏上 人生最盛大的旅程…
Okay, just some pictures of Mrs. Roosevelt
这只是一些罗斯福夫人的照片
that I cut out of the library books during study hall.
我在自习时间从图书馆书上剪的
And I thought that we could put some of our own pictures
我想我们可以放一些自己的照片上去
- and some stuff in the back, too. - Thanks, Max.
还有在后面贴上其他东西 麦斯，谢谢你
Okay.
好的
Close surveillance
经调查指出
of the Soviet military buildup on the island of Cuba
在过去一周内，苏联军队
- within the past week... - This place is a real dump.
正在古巴列岛集结 这地方真破烂
...unmistakable evidence has established the fact that a series of offensive
…有明显证据显示 数个导弹基地
missile sites is now in preparation on that imprisoned island.
已经在岛上设立
The purpose of these bases
看似这些基地的目的
- seems to be none other... - It just ate my quarter again!
只可能是为了… 它又吃了我的钱
...than to provide a nuclear strike capability against the Western hemisphere.
…提供苏联对西半球发动核子攻势的能力
And having now confirmed and completed our evaluation of the evidence
在验证过这些证据
and our decision on a course of action,
并仔细审查我们的选项后
this government feels obliged to report...
政府当局认为有义务…
A rodent just walked through the bathroom. He did not look like the Little Elvis.
一只老鼠刚从浴室穿过 它跟小猫王一点也不像
Well, who did he look like?
不然它看起来像谁？
Like a little Jerry Lee.
比较像小的杰瑞李
Several of them include medium range ballistic missiles.
其中几座配备中距离弹道飞弹
- I think Steve will like this one. - Capable of carrying a nuclear warhead
史提夫会喜欢这个 能发射搭载核弹头的飞弹
for a distance of more than 1,000 nautical miles.
至1000海里远
Each of these missiles, in short,
简而言之，每颗导弹
is capable of striking Washington, D.C.,
都能直接轰炸华盛顿特区
the Panama Canal,
巴拿马运河
Cape Canaveral, Mexico City,
卡纳维尔角，墨西哥市
or any other city in the southeastern part of the United States.
还有美国东南部任何城市
Why is he talking about missiles?
他干嘛要谈飞弹？
In central America, or in the Caribbean area.
中美洲，甚至加勒比海
Additional sites, not yet completed,
目前尚未发现更多基地
appear to be designed for intermediate range ballistic missiles
看起来是专为发射 中距离弹道飞弹
capable of traveling more than...
飞行距离长达…
Capable of striking most of the major cities in the western hemisphere.
并能攻击西半球任何一座重要城市
- Ellie? - My fellow citizens, let no one doubt...
艾莉？ 国民们，不用怀疑…
- Where's the western hemisphere? - ...that this is a difficult
西半球是哪里？ …这个举动
and dangerous effort
将让我们面对
- on which we have set out. - It's right here.
严重且危险的问题 就是这里
No one can foresee precisely what course it will take,
无人能预知未来会发生什么事
and what course or casualties will be incurred.
或是会造成多少人丧命
Many months of sacrifice and self-discipline fie ahead.
接下来的几个月我们必须严以律己
Months in which both our patience...
我们的耐心…
- Commies want us bad, Little E. - ...and our willpower will be tested.
小猫王，共产党很想击败我们 …及信心都将受到考验
God willing, that goal will be achieved.
愿上帝保佑，我们能熬过这次煎熬
Thank you and good night.
谢谢你们的聆听，晚安
I think we should go home.
我想我们应该回家
I'm not going home.
我才不要回家
And besides, even if we did, we'd still be in the western hemisphere.
加上就算我们回去 我们还是在西半球
I knew those Soviets were up to something.
我就知道苏联有什么计划
You know, they've been quiet for a really long time.
他们已经不动声色很久了
- Good night, Ellie. - Good night.
艾莉，晚安 晚安
There it goes!
它又跑过去了
What are you doing out of your house?
你跑出家里干嘛？
I should set you free behind the Bank of America.
我应该在美国银行后面将你放生
But I won't.
但我不会
Max would kill me, and it would ruin my chances with her.
麦斯会杀了我 那也会毁了我追到她的机会
What was I thinking, Little E?
小猫王，我到底在想什么？
What's Mrs. Roosevelt gonna think when those two crazy girls show up?
要是罗斯福夫人突然看到两个疯婆子出现 不知道她会说什么？
They're gonna call the cops and they're gonna get arrested for trespassing.
会有人报警 然后她们就会依非法闯入被逮捕
Then I'll go to Folsom
我也会去佛森监狱坐牢
for forging and impersonating a former First Lady.
罪名是伪造前第一夫人的书信
We have to stop them from ruining my life.
我们得阻止她们毁了我的人生
Yours, too.
还有你的
Jack! Henry!
杰克！亨利！
Where's your mother's piano?
你们妈妈的钢琴跑哪去了？
It's right there, Dad.
爸，就在这边
Right where?
哪边？
- Right where it's always at. - I see it.
就在原地 我看到了
Yeah?
是吗？
Robert!
罗伯！
What, Dad?
爸，怎么了？
Where's the piano?
钢琴跑哪去了？
It's right in front of you, Dad.
就在你前面
Ellie?
艾莉？
She's at Max's.
她在麦斯家
They're working on an outer space project for school.
她们正在写外太空的报告
Yeah, she won't be back until next week.
她下礼拜才会回来
- Where's the baby? - Kitchen.
婴儿呢？ 在厨房
Boys...
男孩们…
Why don't you play something for us on the piano, Dad?
爸，你为何不弹几首歌来听听？
What the hell is the bird doing in the house?
为什么家里有鸟？
Bird? What bird?
鸟？什么鸟？
- Don't you give a hoot no more, Dad? - Yes, son.
爸，你不在意吗？ 孩子们
I give a hoot!
我当然在意！
Zion National Park.
锡安国家公园
- Where'd you put the map? - It's in the back seat.
你把地图放哪了？ 就在后座
- Should be right on top, right? - Yeah.
你应该放在上层吧？ 对
Well, it's...
可是…
- It's not back here. - Yes, it is.
什么都没有 当然有
No, it's not.
没有
- It's not? - No.
没有吗？
I think I left it at home.
我可能忘在家了
- You think anyone's gonna find it? - I don't...
你觉得会有人找到吗？ 我不…
No. No one goes in my room. It's fine.
没人会进我房间，没事的
Yeah, Mrs. Wax, I'm just trying to find my daughter. Boys!
是的，瓦克斯太太 我只是想找我女儿，男孩们！
So, yeah, so unless their project has something to do...
除非她们的功课…
- Dad! - ...with making themselves invisible,
爸！ …跟隐形有关
they're not here. Now I...
她们不在这，换我…
- Dad! - What is it, Jack?
爸！ 杰克，怎么了？
- When Ellie gets back from New York... - Right, yes.
艾莉从纽约回来后… 是的
...can we go to Kentucky Fried Chicken?
…我们能去吃肯德基吗？
It starts here, Manteca, where we are,
她们从这里出发，也就是曼特卡
goes across the entire country,
横跨整个国家
all the way across to Eleanor Roosevelt, okay?
直到爱莲娜罗斯福她家，好吗？
Ellie's gone.
艾莉跑走了
Okay, Johnny, I need you to go put out an APB for me, son. Okay? Real fast.
强尼，我需要你帮我发布全境通告 可以吗？快一点
Fast as you can. Call headquarters.
尽你所能，快打给总部
Hey, you kids listen to your grandma!
嘿，你们要听外婆的话！
That, Mr. President, is the Soviet Foreign Minister's public statement
总统先生，这就是苏联的外交部长 所发布关于苏联政策
about the policy of the Soviet Union and of Cuba in this western...
及这次古巴危机的公开声明…
I told you I knew how to drive, Ellie.
艾莉，跟你说过我会开车了吧
Max, see, for people to sleep, you have to be quiet.
麦斯，你这么吵我可睡不着
...the general assembly on Cuba's foreign policy.
…还有关于古巴的外交政策
Faithful to these principles of his international policy
他们会遵守国际间的守则
and to the principles enshrined in the charter of the United Nations.
跟联合国宪章的准则
Cuba constitutes a danger...
古巴构成危险的…
They're selling radiation-proof huts over at McRooters.
麦鲁特那正在卖抗辐射屋
Get this, Phil's got a scam.
听好，菲尔只会骗人
Selling his cotton briefs as bomb resistant underwear.
她把棉布当防爆内衣卖
Bomb resistant underwear?
防爆内衣？
- That's $9.72. - We should get some.
总共9.72元 我们该买一点
Have you girls seen the news?
你们有看新闻吗？
Yeah. Do you guys sell that here?
有，你们有卖吗？
You girls aren't from around here, are you?
你们不是当地人吧？
- No, we're from California. - California.
不是，我们是加州来的 加州
- That must be nice. - Yeah.
一定是个好地方 对
You have relatives in Colorado?
在科罗拉多州有亲戚吗？
Why are we in Colorado, Max? We went the wrong way.
麦斯，为什么我们在科罗拉多州？ 我们走错路了
Well, which way are we headed now?
不然要往哪走？
North. Where did you go while I was sleeping?
往北，在我睡觉时，你是怎么开的？
Not the right way?
我走错了吗？
Where is it y'all trying to get to anyhow?
你们到底想去哪里？
We're going to see Eleanor Roosevelt. She's a close personal friend.
我们要去找爱莲娜罗斯福 她是我们的好朋友
- Do your parents know where you are? - Yeah, of course, it was their idea.
你们父母知道这件事吗？ 当然，这都是他们的主意
They gave us plenty of money.
他们还给我们一大笔钱
Listen, why don't you come home with me to my ranch?
听着，你们为何不来我家的牧场住几天？
You can stay for a couple of days till we know what's happening.
在事态明朗前待个几天
Call your parents, tell them you're safe.
打给你们父母 告诉他们你们很安全
It's a nice little ranch. I have horses.
我的牧场很不错，我有养马
What do you say?
你们觉得呢？
- Yeah. Okay. - Yeah.
好啊 可以
Totally boss, okay.
超酷的
I'm gonna get... Yeah.
我要买这些
And... And this.
还有…这些
- Max, I already have one. - Steve will like this one, too.
麦斯，这我买了 史提夫也喜欢这个
You having fun, Little E?
小猫王，玩得开心吗？
We gotta go back for him.
我们得回去帮他
Need a ride, sir?
先生，需要搭便车吗？
Billy Hobgood? What the hell are you doing out here?
比利哈古德？ 你在这里干嘛？
I'm just out seeing the sights.
我只是来看风景
Yeah? Well, I'm out here looking for my daughter, and my truck broke down.
是吗？我出来找我的女儿 可是我的车抛锚了
That's what I'm doing.
就是这样
Well, I can give you a ride.
我可以载你一程
In this?
靠这辆车？
- Yes, sir. - Yeah?
是的，先生 真的？
This vehicle make it across country?
你要骑这台车横跨美国？
- I think so. - Yeah?
是的 真的？
- Yeah. - Okay. Good.
真的 好吧
Because I know where they're going. I got their map.
因为我知道她们的目的地 我有她们的地图
My daughter, she's just...
我女儿她…
She's been acting out a little bit lately and just having a hard time,
她最近有点发脾气 而且最近她
and just been dealing with that,
也在面对这些问题
so I called the police and put out an APB, so took care of all that.
我打给警察，请他们发布全境通告 至少这部分我做了
- Really, sir? - Yeah.
先生，真的吗？ 没错
- You did that? - I did.
你这么做了？
Son, you got nothing to do with this, do you? And be honest with me.
孩子，你跟这事没有关系吧？ 跟我老实说
No, sir.
先生，没有
- All right, well, start it up. - Yes, sir.
好的，发动车子吧 先生，好的
I'm not gonna ride in the buddy-seat, though.
我不要坐副驾
You have to, sir.
先生，你必须要坐
- And also, you have to hold the Little Elvis. - Weird kid.
而且你也得抓着小猫王 怪人
And he might poop in your pocket, so don't get too mad.
还有它可能会大便在你口袋里 不要太生气
Max, I don't know if this is a good idea. We don't even know these people.
麦斯，我不确定这是不是好主意 我们根本不认识这些人
She seemed really nice, and I really want a home cooked meal
她人看起来不错 我也很想吃些家常菜
and a bathroom without rodents.
还有没有老鼠的浴室
Hope you girls are hungry. Dinner's almost ready.
希望你们肚子饿了 因为晚餐快准备好了
Yeah, I'm starving.
我快饿死了
This place is great. Can we go horseback riding?
这里真不错 我们能去骑马吗？
Yeah, I'm sure my son can take you out.
当然，我儿子可以带你们出去玩
There he is. Bud! Bud!
他就在那，巴德！
Splendor in the Grass.
《天涯何处无芳草》
- He looks just like... - Warren Beatty.
他长得就像… 华伦比提
Howdy. I'm Bud.
你好，我是巴德
I'm Max.
我是麦斯
- Ellie. - Nice to meet you both.
艾莉 幸会
- They're staying with us... - Bud. Nice to meet you.
她们要待到…
...until we get an all-clear from the President.
…总统发布解除警戒以前
Well, great. Well, welcome.
很好，非常欢迎
- Y'all coming? - Yeah.
你们要一起来吗？ 好
- Charlotte's quite the cook. - Hold this, Max.
夏洛特厨艺很不错 麦斯，拿着
Be sure to call your parents right after dinner and let them know you're okay.
记得吃完晚饭就打给你们父母 让他们知道你们没事
Okay.
好
You're squeezed in mighty tight over there, ain't you?
你们不觉得这样坐有点挤吗？
Do you guys want to hear my greatest idea ever?
你们想听我最伟大的主意吗？
Homing pigeons.
追踪鸽子
Does this have anything to do with what you did to the Little Elvis?
这跟你最近对小猫王做的事有关吗？
No. Take a pigeon, and I drive it to a movie star's house.
没有，抓一只鸽子 然后开车到一个电影明星家
Pick somebody!
选一个人！
Warren Beatty.
华伦比提
I don't think he likes birds, but I like the way you're thinking. Charlotte.
我不认为他喜欢鸟 但我喜欢你的点子，夏洛特
Marlon Brando.
马龙白兰度
Yes, Brando.
没错，白兰度
So, I ride my bike with the pigeon over to Marion's house,
我骑着脚踏车带着鸽子白兰度的家
show her Marlon's house, drive home,
带它看看白兰度的家，然后再回家
and then I write a note that says, "I love you, Marlon Brando.
然后写一张小纸条说 “马龙白兰度，我爱你
"Will you marry me? Check the box, 'yes' or 'no."'
“你愿意娶我吗？ 请选是或否”
Then I tape it to the pigeon's leg
然后把它黏在鸽子的脚上
and it flies to my fiance's house and gives him the note.
它就会飞到我未婚夫的家里 把纸条传给他
Wait, the pigeon gives Marlon the note?
所以鸽子会把纸条给白兰度吗？
Boom. Flying fan-mail.
对，飞天粉丝信
That's impossible, Max.
麦斯，那是不可能的
No, it's not, because I know where we can get a pigeon.
才不是，因为我知道去哪弄鸽子
Yeah, well, the pigeon's not the hard part.
鸽子才不是困难的地方
The making him fly with a note taped to his leg to Marlon Brando's house?
是教它带着纸条 飞到白兰度他家那部分？
- Yeah, that's impossible. - It's impossible.
不可能的 不可能
"Stella!"
“史黛拉！”
I know this guy in Detroit who got a pigeon
我知道有一个人住底特律 他有养一只鸽子
and he drove to his girlfriend's house in Arkansas.
他开到他女朋友位于阿肯色州的家
And then he drove home to Detroit, and the next day
然后再开回底特律，结果隔天
the pigeon showed up on her doorstep in Little Rock.
那只鸽子就出现在 他女朋友位于小岩城的家
There's a million pigeons out there. That could have been any bird in Little Rock.
世界上有几百万只鸽子 小岩城前那只可能只是路边的鸽子
- True. - With a note?
也是 脚上有绑纸条吗？
"I could have been somebody.
“我本来可以出人头地
"I could have been a contender."
“我本来可以当个竞争者”
Y'all want to go squirrel hunting tomorrow?
你们明天想去猎松鼠吗？
Hey, Max?
嘿，麦斯？
I'm pretty sure I saw Frank Morris at the store today.
我确信我今天在店里看到法兰克莫利斯
Who's Frank Morris?
法兰克莫利斯是谁？
The mastermind who escaped Alcatraz.
阿卡翠斯逃犯的首脑
Well, Billy says nobody makes it off Alcatraz alive.
比利说没人能活着逃出阿卡翠斯
Billy doesn't know anything.
比利又不是万事通
Well, why was he on the Rock?
他为何被关在恶魔岛？
I don't know. Probably murder.
不知道，八成是谋杀吧
All I'm saying is,
我的重点是
I'm pretty sure I saw him steal crackers today.
我确定我看到他今天在偷饼干
I need a cigarette.
我需要抽根烟
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
You know, smoking's bad for you.
你知道，抽烟对身体不好
Well, not that it matters.
反正我也不在意
We're all gonna die anyway. After all, this is the western hemisphere.
我们迟早都会死 毕竟，这里可是西半球
Can I bum one?
我可以借根抽吗？
- Yeah. - Thank you.
可以 谢谢你
You look like Warren Beatty.
你看起来就像华伦比提
Do I make you nervous?
我让你感到紧张吗？
No.
没有
- How old are you? - 17.
你几岁了？
You know you're not inhaling that, right?
你知道自己没抽进去吧？
- What? - Here, go like this.
什么？ 跟我这样做
Try it.
试试看
There you go.
就是这样
You got it, you got it right.
你成功了
So, Why'd you run away from home?
你为什么要离家出走？
- I... I didn't. - Sure you didn't.
我…我没有 你绝对没有
You know you can tell me. I ain't gonna turn you in.
你可以对我说真话 我不会打你的小报告
I didn't run away from home. I'm...
我不是离家出走，我只是…
I'm on vacation.
放长假
Hey, you wanna see something cool?
你想看些酷东西吗？
- Yeah. - Yeah? Come on. Let's go.
好啊 那跟我走吧
Come on.
跟好
It's beautiful, huh?
很漂亮吧？
Yeah.
对
They're not 17.
她们才不到17岁
Look at this postcard Max asked me to mail.
看看今天麦斯请我帮她寄的明信片
"Dear Steve, it's your favorite 15-year-old again.
“亲爱的史提夫 又是你最爱的15岁女孩
"I was in the great state of Utah recently.
“我最近刚拜访犹他州
"This is what my motel looked like. Sincerely, Max the Wax."
“我的汽车旅馆就长这样 伟大的瓦克斯敬上”
I mentioned calling their parents, they changed the subject,
我一提到要她们打给爸妈 她们就转移话题
so I'm gonna call the police in the morning.
我一早就打给警察
I think they're runaways.
我想她们是逃家少女
Why don't you call Max's father?
为什么你不打给麦斯的爸爸？
I don't have his phone number.
我没有他的电话号码
You don't have Steve McQueen's phone number.
你没有史提夫麦坤的电话号码
I don't think so.
没有
You better not.
你最好没有
Wake up. We're leaving.
起床了，我们要走了
Why? Did your boyfriend break up with you already?
为什么？你男朋友已经跟你分手了吗？
What? No.
什么？不是
"Dear Steve McQueen, it's your favorite 15-year-old again." That's what it is.
我是指“亲爱的史提夫麦昆 又是你最爱的15岁女孩”
Charlotte thinks we're runaways. She's calling the police.
夏洛特认为我们是逃家少女 她要打给警察
Charlotte's making chocolate chip pancakes for breakfast.
夏洛特早餐要做巧克力豆煎饼
Gosh, we don't have time for chocolate chip pancakes!
天啊，我们没时间吃巧克力豆煎饼
Ellie!
艾莉！
Get up.
给我起来
You kissed him, didn't you?
你亲了他，对吧？
Are you kidding me right now?
你在开玩笑吗？
Why'd you have to tell everyone Steve McQueen's
麦斯，为什么你要告诉别人
- your dad in the first place, Max? - You know,
史提夫麦昆是你的爸爸？ 有时候
sometimes you have to believe stuff like that, Ellie.
这也是非常有可能的
You don't know.
你又不知道
You know, maybe Steve likes my cards, and maybe one day,
说不定史提夫喜欢我的卡片 然后有一天
he'll pick me up in his corvette and give Dave the what's what for a whole day.
他会开着敞篷车 来我家念大卫一整天
And it'll be great...
然后我就可以…
- What was that? - I don't know.
那是什么？ 我不知道
- Max, what was that? - I don't know. You hit it.
麦斯，那是什么？ 我不知道，是你撞的
Oh, my God, it was a squirrel!
我的天啊，是只松鼠！
- No, no, no, no! I killed a squirrel. - You hit a squirrel!
不！我杀了一只松鼠 你撞死一只松鼠
- Why would you do that, Ellie? - Because I was distracted.
艾莉，你干嘛这样？ 因为我分心了
- Well, why were you distracted? - Because you won't stop talking.
为什么你会分心？ 因为你不肯闭嘴
- Oh, my God. - One of the reasons that you like me
我的天啊 你之所以喜欢我
is because I talk!
就是因为我话多
You know what?
猜怎么着？
Are you serious right now?
你认真吗？
I hate to say it, but it's a great addition to the scrapbook.
不是我要说 但这可以帮剪贴簿增加风采
I'm done.
我受够了
- I'm done. Stop! Hush! - You're...
我受够了，住嘴！ 你…
Don't talk.
不要说话
Let's drive in peace, please.
拜托让我安静地开车
This trip is a disaster.
这趟旅途是个灾难
A complete disaster.
惨不忍睹的灾难
- Can we just go see Aunt Daisy now? - Fine. Fine.
我们可以去拜访黛西婶婶了吗？ 随便
Who's Aunt Daisy?
黛西婶婶是谁？
- Stop. Stop. Stop screaming! - We're just kids!
不要再叫了！ 我们还小
Are you the mastermind from Alcatraz?
你不就是阿卡翠斯逃犯的首脑？
- Is that what they're calling me now? - I knew it was you!
他们这么称呼我吗？ 我就知道是你！
I knew it was you, Frank Morris.
我就知道是你，法兰克莫利斯
- It's Frank Morris? - Yes! This is Frank Morris!
这是法兰克莫利斯？ 没错！他就是法兰克莫利斯
- We're going to die. We're gonna die! - I'm not dying in Colorado!
我们会死在这里！ 我不要死在科罗拉多州！
Hold on, no one's going to die. Now calm the hell down.
等一下，没人会死 你们冷静一点
You know what? Before you do this, you should know
在你下手之前，你要知道
that I am just like you, okay?
我跟你一样，好吗？
I put laxative in my teacher's coffee and she was out of school for two days.
我在我老师的咖啡里放泻药 她连续两天没办法来上课
I have a longer rap sheet than you, Frank.
法兰克，我的罪行跟你一样多
I am bad. I am bad, all right? I am... Ellie, I am bad.
我超坏，我超坏的，好吗？ 艾莉，我真的超坏
Max, hey, give him the money.
麦斯，把钱给他
We don't have any money.
我们身上没钱
- Give him the money, Max! - We do not have any money!
麦斯，把钱给他！ 我们没钱！
I don't want your money.
我不要你们的钱
I don't need to go back to prison. I want something else.
我可不想再被关起来 我有其他要求
You are not gonna get any of the money!
你一毛钱都拿不到！
Relax.
放轻松
I just need a ride.
我只是想搭个便车
Okay.
好吧
Now, we're gonna walk in calmly, sit down nicely
我们只要安静地走进去 然后正常地坐下来
and you're gonna act like I'm your pa.
然后装做我是你们的父亲
This is Sunset Boulevard, Los Angeles, California.
这里是加州洛杉矶的落日大道
It's about 5:00 in the morning.
目前是早上五点钟
That's the homicide squad complete with detectives and newspapermen.
我们周围是重案组警探跟各报记者
A murder has just been reported from one of those great big houses...
目击证人指出这栋大房子内发生…
- What are you talking about? - ...on the 10,000 block.
你在讲什么？ …谋杀事件
- Monologue. You can't stop her. - You'll see it in the late editions.
自言自语，没人能阻止她 刊登最新消息
- Monologue? - I'm sure. It'll play over your radio.
自言自语？ 记得收听无线电
And you'll see it on television.
各媒体都会争相报导
Because an old time star is involved.
因为死者包含一名非常有名的
One of the biggest.
电影明星
But before it gets all distorted, blown out of proportion,
但在这则新闻被过度渲染之前
before those Hollywood columnists get their hands on it,
在好莱坞的专栏作家下手之前
maybe you want to hear the facts.
你们应该先听听事实
If so, you've come to the right party.
如果正是如此 那你们就来对地方了
- Make her stop. - I can't. She's gotta finish.
叫她住嘴 办不到，她一定要讲完
You see, a young man was found dead in her mansion swimming pool.
有一位年轻男子 被发现陈尸在她家的游泳池中
Two shots in his back and one in his stomach.
背后中两枪，肚子中一枪
No one important, really.
他不算什么大人物
Just a movie writer with a couple of B pictures to his credit.
只是一个编过几部B级片的小咖
The poor dope. He always wanted a pool.
可怜人，他一直想要自己的游泳池
Well, in the end, he got himself a pool.
他最后也得到了游泳池
Only the price turned out to be a little high.
只是代价比他想像中的高太多
- Hey, Delores. - Hey, how are you? Good to see you.
嗨，迪罗莱 你们好吗？很高兴见到你们
Hey, Officers.
警官好
How's your night going?
晚上情况如何？
Let's sit up near the bar here.
我们就坐在吧台这边
Cool.
好的
You rat me out,
你们供出我
and I'll tell them that you're juvenile delinquent runaways,
我就告诉他们 你们是逃家的青少年犯
and you'll be the ones trying to find your way off Alcatraz.
就换你们要想办法逃出阿卡翠斯
Man, this is tepid.
这都凉了
Hey. Hi.
你好
Can you heat this up for me?
能帮我热一下吗？
And can you also put some more of that "pff, pff," on top? Thanks.
然后请你在上面多放点鲜奶油好吗？ 谢谢你
Coming right up.
马上来
I hear you have to eat slop in prison, Frank. Is that true?
法兰克，听说在监狱里都吃厨余 真的吗？
You say another word and that's all you'll ever eat.
你再说一个字 就不准你吃东西
No more "pff, pff," ever, you hear me?
包括鲜奶油，懂了吗？
I'm in charge now.
我才是老大
Okay.
好
You know, none of this would have happened if you didn't take us on that stupid detour.
要不是你害我们绕远路
- Don't blame me. - Like, didn't you?
不要怪我 不是你干的吗？
Yeah, well, whoop-de-doo.
阿不就好棒棒
That should have been a clue.
那应该是线索
You meet a guy who looks like Warren Beatty and ride a horse.
你遇到一个长得像华伦比提 又会骑马的帅哥
None of that would have happened if it wasn't for me.
要不是我你才不会遇到这种好康
Yeah, if it wasn't for you, I wouldn't be stuck with this guy!
要不是你，我也不会跟这人困在一起！
- Hey, hey, hey. Sit down. - I'm not gonna sit down.
嘿，坐下来 我才不要
If you didn't write that stupid letter to Eleanor Roosevelt in the first place,
要不是你写那封蠢信给爱莲娜罗斯福
we wouldn't be in this predicament right now.
我们也不会遇到这样的困境
I only wrote that letter, Ellie, because I'm your best friend
艾莉，我写那封信 是因为我是你的好朋友
and I didn't want you to end it.
我不想要你自杀
Maybe you just should have, because you're not the only one with problems.
说不定你早该了结
- Thank you. - Come back soon, now.
谢谢 欢迎再度光临
Will you shut up, Max?
麦斯，你可以住嘴吗？
You don't even know what you're talking about.
你在胡言乱语
You kissed Bud when you knew that I liked him.
你明知道我喜欢巴德 你还亲他
- This is about scoring Warren? - Yeah, it's about scoring Warren!
这跟把不把得到华伦有关？ 没错
Sol kissed him. Big deal. We're never gonna see him again.
我亲他有什么大不了的 反正我们再也见不到他了
- Sit down. - I'm not gonna sit down.
坐下 我才不要坐下
- You know one more thing? - I blame you
你知道吗？ 我吃不到巧克力豆煎饼
for not letting me eat those chocolate chip pancakes.
都是你的错
Chocolate chip pancakes! Come on.
巧克力豆煎饼！你嘛帮帮忙
My mom doesn't even care about anything
我妈除了该死的燕麦粥以外
other than stupid Cream of Wheat and I gosh-darn hate it!
什么都不想吃 我恨透那东西了
- She's driving me nuts. - No, you don't!
她快把我逼疯了 你才别想！
- You're welcome. You're crazy! - You're crazy!
不客气，疯婆子！ 你才是疯婆子！
Frank.
法兰克
This is for your own good, okay?
这是为了你好，知道吗？
I thought you knew me better than this, Max.
麦斯，我以为你更了解我
I do.
我是
Besides, I think I like somebody else anyway.
加上我可能喜欢上别人了
Hey, buddy?
兄弟？
I got two kids just like that at home.
我家里的两个小孩就是这熊样
Hey, take a napkin. Clean yourself up.
拿张卫生纸擦干净吧
Cops won't give a reward to a couple of kids.
警察才不会把赏金交给小孩
They'll just say we're runaways and send us home.
他们只会说我们离家出走 然后把我们送回家
Definitely, definitely no cops.
绝对不能找警察
My gosh, here he comes.
天啊，他过来了
- What? - Lock the door.
怎样？ 车门锁好
Come on, open up.
快把门打开
Open the door.
把门打开
- Open the door. - What's on your face?
你脸怎么了？
- No, Alcatraz man.
才不要，阿卡翠斯男
I already bailed you out once.
我已经帮过你一次
- What's he doing? - I don't know!
他在干嘛？ 我不知道！
"Want to hear a story about right-hand, left-hand?
“想要听个关于左右手的故事吗？
"A story about good and evil?"
“一个关于善恶的故事？”
- Okay, I know this one. My gosh! - "H-A-T-E."
天啊，我记得这故事！ “恨”
- It's going to kill me. I know this one. - "It was with this hand
我受不了了，我知道这台词 “就是用这只手
"that old brother Cain struck the blow that laid his brother low.
“哥哥该隐杀了自己的弟弟
"L-O-V-E.
“爱
"You see these fingers, dear hearts?
“我的内心，有看到这些手指？
"The veins go straight to the soul of a man.
“血管直通人的灵魂
"The right hand, the hand of love.
“右手，代表爱的手
"Let me tell you a story, a story about life.
“让我讲个关于生命的故事
"These fingers, they were...
“这些手指，它们…
"They were a-warring and a-fighting,
“它们本来相互争战
"one against the other, and old brother left hand,
“各自对战，然而哥哥左手
"he was a-fighting and it looked like love was a goner,
“它好战成性 看来它心中已没有了爱
"but wait a minute.
“等一下
"Love. Love was a-winning.
“爱，爱即将战胜
"Hot dog, love was the winner.
“爱战胜了
"Old left hand, hate,
“老旧的左手，带着恨意
"he was down for the count."
“被打倒了”
Night of the Hunter, Robert Mitchum!
劳勃米契演的《猎人之夜》
Loved that.
我超爱的
Don't leave me out here.
不要把我留在这里
I think we should take him, Ellie.
艾莉，带他走
Heck, this guy's better than Brando. I can learn a lot from this fellow.
这家伙比白兰度还厉害 我可以跟他学习
- Night of the Hunter, huh? - You got it.
《猎人之夜》，是吗？ 你猜对了
I got it.
我猜对了
Did you work a lot on your fitness in prison, Frank?
法兰克，你在监狱里有健身吗？
Not a lot else to do on the Rock.
看起来在里面
It shows.
也没其他事情做
Is it wrong to think a convict is cute, Ellie?
艾莉，认为一个重犯很帅很奇怪吗？
He's an old man. He's probably already 30.
他很老了，他可能已经30岁了
Everything's A-okay, Mr. Potter.
波特先生，所有事情都乔好了
My parents are glad I'm gone.
我父母很高兴我出门
- Got fired from Dairy Deluxe, though. - It happens.
可是我被豪华餐馆炒了 世道如此
- Can I ask you a question, sir? - Right now?
先生，我能问个问题吗？ 现在吗？
How come you gave up pumpkins?
你为什么要放弃种南瓜？
How come I did what?
我怎么了？
You're not really a farmer anymore, sir. All your pumpkins are rotting.
先生，你不再务农了 你的南瓜也都烂了
I just see you sitting in your truck doing nothing. It's creepy.
我看着你每天呆坐在车里 有点诡异
I don't know why you'd call it creepy, son. I mean,
我不知道你为什么会认为那样很诡异
I don't get the problem you kids have with that truck.
我也不知道你们 跟那台卡车有什么过节
I just enjoy sitting in there and smoking the occasional cigarette.
我只是喜欢坐在里面 享受抽烟的感觉
I like it. Makes me feel good.
让我感觉很舒畅
See, I think you might get confused sometimes because, you know,
我知道你们有时候会很疑惑
you're just a little kid.
因为你们只是小孩
You know, what are you? About 12?
你几岁了？12岁吗？
- Sixteen, sir. - Okay.
先生，我16了 好
Well, see, I'm a grown man,
我是个成年人
and sometimes grown men do things that younger people don't understand.
有时候成年人做的事 年轻人是不会懂的
It doesn't make sense to you 'cause you haven't...
你们不懂是因为…
You haven't been around, and I don't just mean
你们待的时间不够久，我不是指
been around town, I mean you haven't...
待在镇上的时间不够久…
You haven't been alive that long, so you don't really know
你们待在这世上的时间不够久 所以你们不了解
what in the hell's going on a lot of the time, so you get kind of confused like...
世界上发生的狗屁事情 你们就会像你…
Like you do.
一样混乱
But...
但…
I appreciate your being interested in how I spend my private time.
我很感激你有注意到 我在私人时间做的事情
Why don't you finish up?
赶快吃吧？
- We gotta get back out on the road. - Yes, sir.
我们得上路了 好的，先生
You gotta... You gotta keep eating
继续吃
- and just don't talk for a minute, okay? - Yes, sir.
然后不要讲话，好吗？ 好的，先生
Dazzling Daisy's Palace, showtimes, all right, 2:00, 4:00 and 6:00 p.m.
闪亮黛西的皇宫 开场时间下午两点、四点和六点
What time is it, guys?
现在几点了？
- All right, comes to 5 and 30. - It's 1:30.
大约五点半 是一点半
Well, hurry up! We can make it!
快点啊！我们还赶得上！
Charleston Chew? How did you know I like Charleston Chew?
查尔顿糖？ 你怎么知道我喜欢吃？
I want a bite. Everyone likes candy, Frank.
是我想吃的 法兰克，是人都喜欢吃糖
It's not that, it's my favorite.
这是我最喜欢的
If I hear this song again, I'm gonna kill someone.
要是我再听到这首歌 我会杀人
- That's not funny, Frank. - Relax, it's just a euphemism.
法兰克，不好笑 放轻松，那只是委婉的说法
- What's a euphemism? - A nicer way of saying something.
什么是委婉？ 就是不伤人的说法
- Like, lovin' them up? - Yeah.
譬如说给他们爱意？ 没错
Frank, guess what I just did.
法兰克，猜猜我刚刚做了什么
I don't know. What?
什么？
I just ate a peanut M&M with two nuts in it.
我刚吃到巧克力里面有两颗花生
So, tell me about this Aunt Daisy.
告诉我你黛西婶婶的事
She was a big Broadway showgirl until she married my Uncle Rocko,
在嫁给罗科叔叔之前 她是百老汇的有名舞女
and he thought it would be better for her career to move to Las Vegas.
他认为自己在拉斯维加斯会更有发展 就搬到那边
She's the best in the business, Frank, and an amazing dancer.
法兰克，她是业界顶尖的人 舞技也非常惊人
Great, make it fast. I want to get back on the road.
好吧，不要拖时间 我想尽快赶上路
You're not coming in, Frank. You're staying in the car.
法兰克，你不能跟 你得待在车里
Fine. I don't want to see some old lady doing the splits with a hula-hoop anyway.
好吧，反正我也不想看老女人边劈腿 边玩呼拉圈
I gotta say, it looks better in the movies.
我得说，实际风景比电影里还漂亮
Where's Frank Sinatra and the Rat Pack and the dancing women?
法兰克辛纳屈 还有老鼠帮跟跳舞女郎们呢？
Where's Bugsy and his bulletproof office?
巴格西跟他的防弹办公室呢？
Max, you didn't think we were going to Las Vegas, Nevada, did you?
麦斯，你不会真的以为 我们要去内华达州的拉斯维加斯吧？
Are there two Las Vegases?
有两个拉斯维加斯？
- Yeah.
没错
And the one Aunt Daisy lives in, that's Las Vegas, New Mexico.
黛西婶婶住的是 新墨西哥州的拉斯维加斯
All right.
好吧
This is certainly a full house.
人到是挺多的
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们
Let's give a warm Las Vegas welcome for the star of the show, Dazzling Daisy!
献出你们拉斯维加斯的热情 让我们欢迎大明星，闪亮黛西！
Let's go find her. Come on.
我们快去找她吧
Max, are we supposed to be in here?
麦斯，我们能进来吗？
She's my aunt. I can do what I want.
她是我婶婶，没人管得了我
Gone with the Wind.
《乱世佳人》
This is like Clark Gable's suit! We should get this for Frank!
这是克拉克盖博的西装！ 我们应该偷给法兰克穿！
- This is her stuff. - I'm going to get it on the way out.
这是她的东西 我离开时顺便拿走
Jeez, she's got a lot of stuff.
天啊，她东西真多
Aunt Daisy, are you back here? It's your favorite niece, Maxine!
黛西婶婶，你在这吗？ 你最爱的侄女来找你了！
Maxie?
小麦？
- Is it really you? - Yeah.
真的是你吗？ 当然
Honey!
甜心！
What are you doing here?
你在这干嘛？
Well, my friend Ellie and I are on our way to New York.
我朋友艾莉跟我正要去纽约
We decided to stop by.
我们刚好路过
- Ellie, this is my Aunt Daisy. - Hi. Nice to meet you.
艾莉，这位是黛西婶婶 幸会
- I like your show. - Thank you.
我喜欢你的表演 谢谢
I just started incorporating the whole hula-hoop thing and, you know,
我才刚加入呼拉圈这段
you just never know how it's gonna turn out.
没办法预料观众会有什么反应
Sensational. Do you live here? With all this stuff?
精采绝伦，你住这吗？ 还有这堆东西？
Well, you know, it needs a bit of straightening,
虽然需要整理一下
but I couldn't imagine parting with any of it.
但我不想丢掉任何一件
This is one of my favs.
这是我最喜欢的衣服之一
Worn by the Sandra Church in Gypsy.
是珊卓邱契在《吉普赛女郎》中穿过的
What about this pizza box? Can you get rid of this pizza box?
披萨盒呢？ 至少能把它丢掉吧？
Give it to me.
拿给我
So, where did you put Uncle Rocko?
罗科叔叔要住哪？
He vamoosed a long time ago when he couldn't fit through the door.
他很久以前就离开了 那时候他连门都过不去
Would you girls like some tea and cookies?
你们想喝些茶和吃点饼干吗？
Yeah.
好
Great. Coming right up.
马上来
Look. She circles dance auditions, but then she just crosses them out.
快看，她圈出跳舞征选 然后又把它们划掉
This one's for next week. In New York.
下礼拜还有一个，就在纽约
We have to get her to go to that audition, Ellie.
艾莉，我们得带她去
All right, catch the cookies.
小心，接住饼干
My goodness.
我的老天啊
- And the tea? - What?
还有茶呢？ 什么？
I'm just kidding. I'm not crazy.
开玩笑，我又不是疯子
Well, I might be a little crazy, but not that crazy.
我可能有点疯 但还没真的疯掉
So, New York City.
纽约市
My goodness, I love New York.
我爱死纽约了
Yeah, it's just...
只是…
It's really lonely on the road, isn't it, Max?
麦斯，路上不觉得有点寂寞吗？
I have an idea. Why don't you come with us, Aunt Daisy?
我有个想法 黛西婶婶，你为什么不跟我们一起来？
- That's a great idea, Max. - Isn't that a great idea?
麦斯，那真是个好主意 是不是很聪明？
No. I can't go with you guys to New York.
不行，我不能跟你们去纽约
- You won't be gone for long. - Yeah. Just think of it as a holiday.
又不会去太久 把这当成一场假期
I can't leave all this.
我不能抛弃这一切
You need to do this. You see this audition here?
你必须跟我们去 你没看到这场征选吗？
You're gonna make this audition, and we're gonna help you get there.
你一定会赶上 我们会把你送过去
Daisy, you have to get back out there.
黛西，你必须重出江湖
You don't belong here, on this stage. You need to be on the big stage.
你的舞台不在这种地方 你适合更大的舞台
The big stage.
大舞台
Rise and shine.
起床罗
I got you a present.
我帮你带了个礼物
- Who the hell is this? - I'm Daisy.
她是谁？ 我是黛西
- Daisy, this is... - Daisy.
黛西，这位是… 黛西
- My acting coach. - Max's acting coach,
我的演技指导 麦斯的演技指导
- Lee Strasberg. - Yeah.
李史特拉斯堡 没错
You're not Lee Strasberg.
你才不是李史特拉斯堡
I met Lee Strasberg, and you don't look a thing like him.
我见过他本人 你跟他一点也不像
You look familiar, though.
你看起来倒挺面熟的
- Must be a different Lee Strasberg. - Must be.
一定只是刚好同名 一定
All right, New York, here we come.
好了，纽约，我们要来罗
I gave Lee a couple of egg rolls, but he said he'd be fine just sleeping in the car.
我给李几根蛋卷
We should just say, "Dear Ed."
我们应该就写 “亲爱的艾德”
You can't just call him Ed. Just say, "Dear Mr. Sullivan."
你不能叫他艾德 你应该写“亲爱的苏利文先生”
Ed is more personal, Ellie.
艾莉，艾德听起来比较亲密
What are you two bickering about?
你们在吵什么？
Trying to get on The Ed Sullivan Show, so we can show him our dance.
我们只是想上艾德苏利文秀 向他展现我们的舞步
- Your dance? - It's a tribute to the late, great
你们的舞步？ 这是为了致敬刚去世的大人物
Marilyn Monroe.
玛丽莲梦露
I want to see your dance.
我想看你们跳舞
Yeah, put on the record.
去放歌
Well, it'd be much better on a big stage, but okay.
在大舞台上效果会更好，但是好吧
- Good, Ellie? - Yeah.
好了吗？ 好了
How was that?
如何？
- Amazing. - Let's do it for Eleanor Roosevelt.
很精彩 我们要跳给爱莲娜罗斯福看
- Showed it to our friend Billy once. - But he didn't say anything.
我们也跳给比利看过 但他没什么想法
Okay, it's your turn. Max, get her record.
换你了 麦斯，去拿她的唱片
Yeah!
对！
- This one? - Yeah.
这首？ 没错
Any song but that song.
除了那首以外都行
You know, as a matter of fact, I'm not gonna dance tonight.
老实说，我今天晚上不跳了
Harry Truman called Eleanor Roosevelt the First Lady of the world.
哈利杜鲁门称爱莲娜罗斯福 为世界的第一夫人
She answered the door to the White House herself.
她在白宫会亲自应门
When she wanted to learn how to fly,
当她想学开飞机时
she got Amelia Earhart to promise to teach her.
她叫爱蜜莉亚艾尔哈特答应要教她
She could only cook scrambled eggs, and served them on Sundays for dinner.
她只会做炒蛋 星期天的晚上她就做这道菜
And when the KKK put a bounty on her head, she put a pistol on the car seat
当三K党悬赏她时 她就在置物柜里放把手枪
and drove to Tennessee to speak on civil rights anyway.
并照样开到田纳西州 大谈人权
Eleanor Roosevelt stood down the Klan.
爱莲娜罗斯福逼退了三K党
Good evening,
各位先生女士们
ladies, gentlemen
还有尊贵的贵宾们
and distinguished guests.
晚上好
Mrs. Roosevelt says
罗斯福夫人曾说过
you gain strength,
你能得到力量
- courage... - You all right, Ellie?
与勇气… 艾莉，你没事吧？
Yeah.
没事
What have you got there?
你手上拿什么？
It's just a speech.
只是一份讲稿
I'm just having a hard time memorizing it all.
我有点背不太起来
Is that why you girls want to go to New York?
这是你们要去纽约的原因吗？
So you can deliver a speech to Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt?
能对爱莲娜罗斯福女士演讲？
- Sort of. - That's exciting.
算是吧 真刺激
I guess.
我想也是
My mom was gonna do it before she died.
我妈本来要自己讲的 但她过世了
I didn't tell Max just because, you know, if I can't do it,
我没告诉麦斯是因为 如果我办不到
or if I chicken out...
或是我怯场…
She just thinks we're going over there to visit her
她以为我们只是要去她家
and look at her gardens or something.
看看她的花园之类
Why do you not like the dance Max gave you?
为什么你不喜欢麦斯帮你挑的那支舞？
I haven't really danced full out like that since I was 19 years old.
我从19岁以后 就没有跳那么难的舞了
But you danced in Las Vegas.
但你在拉斯维加斯还有在跳舞
Yeah, I mean, I can cha-cha-cha all day long.
我当然可以摆臀一整天
It's not the hardest thing in the world.
又不是非常难
Remember that outfit I showed you?
记得我给你们看的服装吗？
- The one from Gypsy? - Yeah.
《吉普赛女郎》那件？ 没错
I was supposed to play the lead in Gypsy for the Broadway premiere.
我本来要在那出秀的百老汇首映担纲主角
What happened?
结果呢？
Opening night came.
首映当晚
And when it came time for the big number,
当换我上场时
I couldn't remember a step. Not one.
我一个舞步都记不起来
And the audience started laughing.
然后观众就开始大笑
That's awful.
真惨
And then the stage hand dragged me
然后我就一路掉
all the way to Las Vegas.
掉到拉斯维加斯
Turned out to be Las Vegas, New Mexico,
结果却是新墨西哥州的拉斯维加斯
of all places.
那么多地方可以挑
- Rocko? - Yeah.
罗科？ 没错
That Rocker.
罗科
He wasn't all that bad, you know.
他不完全是个烂人
He built me the theater because he knew how much I missed it.
他帮我搭了一个剧场 因为他知道我很想念那种感觉
But I never found the confidence I had as a girl.
但我再也找不回年轻时的自信
Max is right.
麦斯说的没错
I gotta do this because if I don't at least try, then I'm really finished.
我得放手一搏，要是我连试都没试 我才真的玩完了
I really want to do this for my mom.
我只想为了我妈去做这件事
Make her proud of me, you know?
让她我为傲，你能了解吗？
I've just never done a speech before, or...
只是我从没演讲过，或…
Or anything.
或是任何事
Let's make a deal, all right?
我们来约法三章，好吗？
If I do it, you do it.
要是我去，你也要去
Pinky swear.
打勾勾
Okay.
好
You can do this.
你办得到
Come here.
给我抱一下
Police! Open up!
警察！开门！
- I swear, if that's Frank... - That Frank.
我发誓，如果那是法兰克… 可恶的法兰克
Eleanor Potter and Max the Wax?
爱莲娜波特跟伟大瓦克斯？
- We've been caught. - Runaways, huh?
我们被抓到了 逃家，是吧？
- All the way from California. - Are you gonna book us?
从遥远的加州 你们要逮捕我们吗？
- On what charges? - Juvenile delinquency.
什么罪？ 青少年行为不良
You missed school, you're underage,
你们不只未成年，还翘课
and you've given your parents a first-class heart attack.
还有让你们父母差点心脏病死掉
Now come on, get dressed and get your things together.
快把衣服穿好 然后东西收一收
We're taking you downtown right now.
你们要来警局一趟
What? Where? All right, we'll be there as soon as we can.
什么？哪里？ 好，我们尽快赶过去
Okay, they found them in Kentucky.
他们在肯塔基州找到她们
If we get on, we can get there in a couple of hours, put an end to all this.
要是我们继续赶路 不用几小时就赶得到，一切就结束了
Let's hustle, Hobgood, come on. There you go.
哈古德，加油一点 就是这样
- This stinks. - Your dad's on his way.
糟透了 你爸正在路上
Hey, copper, how did you find us?
条子，你是怎么找到我们的？
"Dear Steve, how are you? I am fine.
“亲爱的史提夫，你好吗？我很好
"I'm in Las Vegas, New Mexico, and I ate an enchilada.
“我在新墨西哥州的拉斯维加斯 刚吃了一个墨西哥卷饼
"It was real good. Talk to you soon. Love Maxine."
“真的很好吃 再联络，爱你的小麦”
Here's another one all the way from Oklahoma.
还有另一张从奥克拉荷马州寄出的
"Dear Steve, guess what I saw today? Two midgets on a motorcycle.
“亲爱的史提夫，猜猜我今天看到什么？ 两个骑摩托车的侏儒
"I've never seen that before. Wish you were here.
“我这辈子没见过这种事 希望你也在这
"Love, Maxine."
“爱你的小麦”
And there's another one, and another one, and another one.
还有另一张 跟这一张，跟这一张
How did you get my cards?
为什么有我的明信片？
We have our ways.
我们自有方法
Max, what is wrong with you?
麦斯，你到底有什么问题？
I'm sorry. I didn't think that we'd get caught.
抱歉，我以为我们不会被抓
I should have never gone on that stupid trip with you.
我从头到尾就不该跟你一起出远门
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean to. - Yeah, no, you're always sorry.
抱歉，我不是故意的 才怪，你总是在抱歉
Girls!
女孩们！
- Mom!
妈妈！
I've been worried sick!
我快担心死了！
Officer.
警官
Sorry, ma'am, I can only release them to their father, Bob Potter.
抱歉，夫人，只有她们的父亲 波特先生可以带他们走
What? No. But...
什么？可是…
But... Dear God!
联邦调查局通缉犯 法兰克李莫利斯
He's sleeping in the car and he gets so mad when we wake him.
他在车里睡觉 如果我叫他起床，他会发脾气
Sorry, ma'am, you'll have to wake him.
抱歉，夫人 你必须叫他起床
I have to have his signature on the release.
我必须让他在释放书上签名
God! Really?
天啊！真的吗？
Yes, ma'am.
是的，夫人
Well, girls,
好吧，女孩们
looks like I have to go wake your father. He's going to be very upset.
看来我得叫你们父亲起床了 他会大发脾气
He is gonna tan your little hides.
屁股等着遭殃吧
Here I am.
我来了
Bob Potter.
鲍勃波特
- Where do I sign? - Right here.
我要签哪？ 就在这
- Hi, Daddy. - Gee, that's a nice suit, Dad.
嗨，爸爸 爸，你穿的西装真帅
You two are in deep trouble.
你们两要倒大楣了
Get your stuff. Let's go.
把东西拿好，我们要走了
Okay.
好吧
Wait, wait, wait. Okay.
等我
You all lied to me. I didn't know you were runaways.
你们对我说谎 我不知道你们离家出走
I mean, I knew you weren't Lee Strasberg,
我早就知道你不是李史特拉斯堡
but I didn't know you were the man from Alcatraz. Gee whiz.
但我也不知道 你就是阿卡翠斯的逃犯
You two were hilarious. You should start up a comedy team.
你们两搞笑极了 你们该组一个搞笑团队
How did y'all get that money?
你们的钱是哪来的？
Ellie stole it.
艾莉偷的
I didn't steal anything. I sold something.
我才没用偷的，我把某件东西卖了
That's the thing, see? You're just helping out a guy.
重点来了，你们在帮的人
A guy who went to the Rock for stealing something.
就是因为偷东西被送去蹲苦牢
We're three of a kind.
我们三人都一副德性
What do you mean, my wife picked her up?
你说我太太接走她们是什么意思？
She did. She left here with you.
她接走了，还跟你一起离开
No.
不
She didn't. That's impossible you see, because I'm here, right now, with you.
她没有，那是不可能的 因为我就站在你面前
- And my wife, well, she... - Is dead.
我老婆她… 过世了
You let strangers kidnap my daughter?
你让陌生人带走我女儿？
- Now, Mr... - What do these people look like?
先生，请你… 他们长什么样？
Was it this lady?
是这女的吗？
- Was it her? - Was it this lady?
是她吗？ 是吗？
Look at it.
快看
That's Eleanor Roosevelt.
那是爱莲娜罗斯福
- Yes, it is. We know that. - No shit.
没错，我们知道 还用你说
You two little ladies, what are y'all running from?
你们两位为什么要逃家？
Nothing.
没什么
No, you shouldn't run away. You're lucky.
你们不该逃家，你们很幸运
I grew up on the streets making every bad choice a kid could make.
我在街头长大 一路犯下各种错误
I've been in and out of prison from the time I was 13 years old.
从13岁起就从监狱进进出出
I was inside longer than I was on the outside.
我在里面待的时间 比外面还久
Do you know this is the first road trip I ever took?
你们知道这是我人生第一次公路旅行吗？
My first road trip.
我第一趟公路之旅
I gotta say,
我得说
I'm having a heck of a time.
我玩得真开心
All right, well,
好吧
half hour to sunrise.
再半小时就要日出了
Frank!
法兰克！
Why don't you just put the mustache back on and come with us to New York?
为什么你不继续戴假胡子 然后跟我们一起去纽约？
Can't do it, Max.
麦斯，我办不到
Can't do it.
恕难从命
You could mastermind Alcatraz, but you couldn't mastermind us.
你能逃离阿卡翠斯 却没办法掌控我们
Nobody could mastermind you two.
没人能掌控你们
And Daisy?
还有黛西呢？
Knock 'em dead.
一路顺风
I hope they never find you, Frank!
法兰克，希望他们永远找不到你！
- Yeah, me, too, Frank! Bye! - Bye!
我也是，法兰克再见！ 再见
- So long, Frank! - Bye, Frank!
法兰克，后会有期！
All right, let's go. Get in the car, you knuckleheads.
走吧，快进车里 你们这对傻蛋
You lock up Elvis Jr.?
你把猫王二世关起来？
It's the Little Elvis, and, yep, he's in the tub.
是小猫王，没错 它正待在浴缸里
He ain't going nowhere. I mentioned to him that we're in Kentucky.
哪里都跑不了 我跟它讲过我们在肯塔基州
He just couldn't believe it. So close to Graceland, yet so far.
它觉得难以置信 离恩赐之地这么近，却无从接近
- You talk to Little Elvis, do you, Billy? - Yeah, I do.
比利，你会跟小猫王对话吗？ 我会
And he wants to know why you stopped farming pumpkins.
它也想问你为什么要放弃种南瓜
Give me a break, son, okay? Been a hell of a long day.
放我一马，好吗？ 这是漫长的一天
Not in the mood to talk about pumpkins.
没心情聊南瓜的事
My daughter's been kidnapped by a strange woman.
我女儿被一个陌生女性带走
Could be Eleanor Roosevelt.
有可能是爱莲娜罗斯福
And Franklin. And you should be happy about that.
还有法兰克林 你应该为此感到开心
- Franklin's dead. - Yeah, well they're both Democrats.
法兰克林死了 但他们俩都是民主党人
That's way better than just plain old Americans.
那比一大堆老美国人好多了
Leave me alone. Let me think. Thinking portion of the night, okay?
安静一点，让我思考 这是夜晚的思考时间，好吗？
- Gotta formulate a plan. - Okay.
一定得想出个计划 好吧
Little Elvis says you have a gift for gourds.
小猫王说你可以种葫芦
And once a farmer, always a farmer. You can't just stop and be something else.
农夫是要当一辈子的 你不能中途转换跑道
- He says you gave up on life. - Tell Little Elvis to kiss my ass.
它说你这是放弃人生 叫小猫王去吃屎
I think he's right.
它说的没错
You shouldn't smoke in bed.
你不应该在床上抽烟
You know, growing up, there was a boy on the farm next to us.
我小时候，隔壁田住了一个小男孩
Nice kid, simple, though, like you.
他就跟你一样，非常单纯
We wouldn't let him near any of the farm equipment.
我们不让他靠近任何农具
Wouldn't even let him sit on a turned off tractor.
连拖拉机也不会让他发动
Now, here I am, riding cross-country with you, coast to coast.
我现在却跟你一起横跨美国 从西岸到东岸
You driving.
还让你骑车
Life's funny.
真好笑
Well, not funny, but unpredictable.
不能算是好笑 只是我真没预料到
Well, I know about life.
我也了解人生
- No, I know. - I also know about family.
我真的了解 我也清楚家人的关系
And how important it is to make sure that they know how much you love them.
要让家人们知道我们的爱 这是非常重要的事
And that they're connected to something.
让他们知道彼此的联系
And it ain't enough for you to just go and find Ellie and bring her home.
光是把艾莉带回家是不够的
Gotta make sure that she has a real home to come back to.
你要确保她想自己回家
My gosh, Ellie, you better hurry up because we're going to be late.
天啊，艾莉，你快一点 我们快迟到了
We're going to miss the audition. We're already a little late.
我们会错过征选 我们已经有点迟到了
- This is it? - It's pretty.
就是这？ 真漂亮
- I like it. So ready for this audition. - Okay.
我很喜欢，我准备万全 好了
Let's go, let's go.
快走吧
Okay.
好的
- All right, where's the dressing room? - We don't have time for a dressing room.
好吧，更衣室在哪？
Come on, let's just get you dressed, Daisy.
黛西，我们得帮你换衣服
- Here? - Yeah!
就在这？ 当然！
- Just put this on! - All right. Unzip me.
快把它穿上！ 好了，帮我拉拉链
- Sorry. - It's too tight. I gotta breathe!
抱歉 太紧了，我没办法呼吸！
Do you wanna get the part or not?
你到底想不想选上？
All right. No breathing.
好了，不要呼吸
- What do you think? - It's great.
你觉得呢？ 美呆了
Here. Here.
这边
- Fluff, fluff, fluff. - All right.
蓬蓬的 好了
Hey, look at me.
看我这边
A deal's a deal, all right?
我们约法三章了，对吧？
Pinky swear.
还有打勾勾
You got this.
你办得到
- I have your record. - Here's your record.
我有带你的唱片 就在这边
Just one more breath.
再深呼吸
No, no, no. Okay.
没事的
- You can breathe on the way. - Breathe on the way.
路上再深呼吸 对
- Let's go. Let's go. - Yeah.
走吧 好
- I'm actually pretty nervous. - You're going to do great. Great.
我其实满紧张的 你会表现得很好
Nerves are fine. Nerves are good.
你的衣服很漂亮 黛西，你的衣服美极了
Hi, hello there. Sorry.
你们好，抱歉
You the 10:00?
你就是十点那位？
- Daisy. - Nice to meet you, Daisy.
黛西 幸会，黛西
Let's get started.
我们开始吧
- You're late. - Yes, sir. I'm aware of that, sir.
你迟到了 先生，我很明白
She's not a mind reader.
她可不会读心
- Excuse me? - Just hand her the record.
对不起？ 把唱片交给她
Could you give her the record, sweetie?
甜心，能把唱片交给她吗？
- The record? - Yes, yes, yes, sorry.
唱片？ 对，很抱歉
- Sorry. - Whenever you're ready.
抱歉 你随时可以开始
You got this, Aunt Daisy.
黛西婶婶，你行的
She's incredible.
她棒极了
That was very nice.
表现很不错
- Thank you so much. - Very nice.
非常感谢 表现得很好
It was the best audition. They loved you. I could tell.
所有人中表现最好的 我看得出来他们很爱你
Those directors went nuts.
这些导演看呆了
They were smiling, they were studying you the entire time.
他们边笑 边观察你每个细节
Mrs. Wax?
瓦克斯夫人？
We're going to need some more information from you.
我们得留下一些你的联络资料
- Go. - Great.
快去 好的
- Aunt Daisy? - Yes.
黛西婶婶？ 是
From now on, no more Las Vegas, New Mexico.
从现在开始 你不用再待在新墨西哥州的拉斯维加斯
I love you so much.
我好爱你们
Never give up on your dreams, sweetheart.
甜心，永远不要放弃自己的梦想
You're bound for something big.
你们注定会做大事
And you.
还有你
You give Eleanor Roosevelt the introduction of a lifetime.
你要帮爱莲娜罗斯福 做史上最好的开场
Okay.
好的
Make your mother proud.
让你妈以你为傲
I'm going to miss her.
我会想她
So long, Aunt Daisy!
黛西婶婶，后会有期！
All right, let's go.
好了，走吧
Looking for these?
在找这些吗？
You found them?
你找到了？
Yeah, you left them in the motel when the copper snagged us.
对，我们在汽车旅馆被条子抓的时候 你留下来的
I know it's your mom's speech, Ellie.
我知道这是你妈的演讲稿
I know what you're doing.
我知道你的计划
You think it's stupid, what I'm doing?
你觉得我很蠢吧？
No, I don't think what you're doing is stupid at all.
不，我觉得一点也不蠢
I actually think that it's pretty spectacular.
我认为那还满棒的
I know, I was...
我知道，我只是…
I should have told you. I should have told you what I was doing,
我早该告诉你我的计划
and I didn't, and out of everyone, you would have probably understood the most.
但我没有，但所有人之中 就你最有可能了解我
Probably would have.
的确
Sorry I've been blaming everything on you, and I've been such an awful friend.
抱歉我最近把气都发在你身上 还有当个很糟的朋友
You know, I know that this was supposed to be this really fun road trip,
我知道这趟旅途本该要很好玩
and I know I haven't been a lot of fun lately.
但我最近一直很扫兴
Ralph Waldo Emerson says that
拉尔夫沃尔多爱默生说过
a friend is someone with whom you can be the most sincere.
只有对你最真挚的人 才能称其为朋友
But I prefer that you only meet your once-in-a-lifetime friend once in a lifetime.
但我希望你一辈子 只要认识一个一生挚友
And that's from The Little Rascals.
节录于《小捣蛋》
You know, you're my once-in-a-lifetime friend, Max.
麦斯，你就是我的一生挚友
You know, I don't really think you need these, Ellie.
艾莉，我认为你不需要这些笔记
I heard you rehearsing the other night. I think you've got it memorized.
我听过你的练习 我认为你都背好了
You think I can do it?
你认为我真的能行？
What's happening?
怎么了？
I don't know.
我不知道
Excuse me?
不好意思？
What's happening?
怎么了？
Didn't you hear?
你们不知道吗？
Eleanor Roosevelt died last night in her sleep.
爱莲娜罗斯福昨晚 于睡梦中过世
Wait. Wait, Ellie.
等一下，艾莉
Let's take one more picture.
我们再拍一张照
Wait, Max, the guards.
麦斯，等一下，有警卫
I'll distract them.
我来转移他们注意力
She really had a way with people.
她待人处事真的很有一套
I still can't believe it.
我还是无法相信
Sir?
先生？
Is the news true?
新闻上讲的是真的吗？
Is it true?
真的吗？
Get back. Get back, please.
请大家退后
- Please stay back. Are you okay, miss? - No, I am not okay.
大家退后，小姐，你还好吗？ 我一点也不好
Sam! Sam, come here.
山姆！山姆，快过来
- Can I get you anything? - I am not okay.
你需要什么吗？ 我一点也不好
- Sam, will you go get me some water? - She stood down the Klan.
山姆，去拿些水好吗？ 她逼退了三K党
Good evening,
各位先生
ladies,
女士们
gentlemen
还有贵宾们
and distinguished guests.
晚上好
Mrs. Roosevelt says you gain strength,
罗斯福夫人说过
courage
透过正视恐惧
and confidence
你就能从各种经验
by every experience in which you really look fear
获得力量、勇气
in the face.
和自信
Why?
为什么？
What the...
为什…
Busted.
要被抓包了
Come with me, young lady.
小姐，请你跟我来
- Give me a second. - I'm sorry,
等一下 我很抱歉
but we're going to have to break this up now.
但闹剧结束了
Thank you very much for paying your respects,
非常谢谢你们特意过来
- but it's time to go home. - Thank you.
该回家了 谢谢
Thank you. Come with me.
谢谢你们，你跟我来
I stand before you tonight,
今晚我在大家面前
doing the thing
来做出
I thought I could not do.
我本认为自己办不到的事
Speaking before an audience of over 200,
在超过200人面前演说
introducing the woman who has meant so much to me and so many others,
为你们介绍在我这辈子中 影响我及众人非常深远的一位女性
and having raised a daughter who I am so proud of.
还有养育一位我非常引以为傲的女儿
And now,
现在
it is my great honor
是我的荣幸
to introduce to you
为你们介绍
the greatest First Lady this country has ever known,
这国家历史上最伟大的第一夫人
the greatest champion of human rights
人权史上最伟大的斗士
and a wonderful mother,
还有一位和蔼的母亲
Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt.
爱莲娜罗斯福女士
I did it, Mama.
妈，我办到了
And I left nothing out.
我一个字都没忘
How long have you been standing there?
你们站在那多久了
Long enough, young lady. Now I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
小姐，站得够久了 现在我得请你们离开
Your dad is here. We drove across the country together.
你爸来了 我们一起骑车横跨美国
It was a little weird at first, but I think we're friends now.
一开始有点奇怪 但我想我们已经变成好朋友
Come here.
过来这边
Honey.
甜心
I'm so glad you're safe.
我很庆幸你没事
I'm here to take you home, okay?
我是来带你回家的，好吗？
I don't know what I'm doing. I need your help.
我不知何去何从 我需要你的帮忙
I mean, your brothers are like little wild animals.
你的弟弟们就像一堆小野兽
I wake up, the little one's just staring at me with those goggles on.
我一起床，最小的就站在我床边 戴着防风镜看着我
Where the hell did he get those goggles?
他是从哪弄来防风镜？
- I don't know. - And he doesn't speak.
我不知道 他一个字也不说
We can do it, though.
不过我们办得到
Did you find what you were looking for?
你有找到要找的东西吗？
I think so.
我想有吧
That's good.
那就好
So did I.
我也是
Okay.
好
Max, I took care of the Little Elvis for over 3,000 miles,
麦斯，我有照顾好小猫王 还带它走了4828公里
and I wouldn't have done that for anybody but you because I like you.
我不是对谁都这样，只有你 因为我喜欢你
Driving home with my dad, Max and Billy,
跟我爸、麦斯还有比利开回家
I looked out the window and saw Marilyn Monroe and my mother
我望向车窗外 看到玛丽莲梦露和我妈
speeding by in Marilyn's pink Thunderbird.
开着玛莉莲的粉红色雷鸟呼啸而过
And I knew right then that I was gonna be okay.
当下我就知道，我不会有事的
And the red line highways
红线高速高路
would link us state by state until it brought us safely back to California.
会一州接一州带我们 安全地回到加州
Back to the pumpkin capital of the world.
回到世界的南瓜首府
All in the western hemisphere.
全部都在西半球的范围内
Ellie! Guess what we got with a postmark from Ireland?
艾莉，猜猜是谁 从爱尔兰寄明信片过来？
"Dear girls, having the time of my life.
“亲爱的女孩们，我过得非常好
"I wish you were here. Guess what?
“希望你们也在这
"I just ate a peanut M&M with two peanuts in it.
“猜怎么着？ 我也吃到有两颗花生的巧克力
"Your friend and partner in crime, Lee Strasberg."
“你们的朋友与犯罪同伙 李史特拉斯堡敬上”
Give me a hand, lover boy. Hand the baby over.
痴情男，把婴儿交出去 过来帮我一下